<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:57:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Micro-Attestation: Proving Digital Content Existence & Origin]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=ObehueZzjK7wqdnImC-qcJtQA5wqGUdKKX_CHiOkCrXDGg0LuU10UIn3V5e4tsyY</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=ObehueZzjK7wqdnImC-qcJtQA5wqGUdKKX_CHiOkCrXDGg0LuU10UIn3V5e4tsyY</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 13:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indie Software Developers,\n\nThe digital landscape is awash with information, making content authenticity and origin increasingly challenging to verify. In the era of AI-generated content and rapid information spread, establishing a clear link between a creator, their identity, and their work is paramount. This year's idea provides a foundational tool in this space, focusing on the intersection of AI (future proofing), Journalism (the nature of the content), and Digital Identity (proving origin).\n\n<strong>Brief Description:</strong>\nBuild a simple web application that allows content creators – think journalists, bloggers, researchers – to "attest" their digital content. This means creating a verifiable record linking a specific piece of content (text, image, document) to a particular digital identity (the creator) at a specific point in time. It's about creating a rudimentary, private ledger of original creation timestamps linked to identities.\n\n<strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong>\nProvides content creators with a lightweight, simple tool to establish proof-of-creation timestamps for their work. This acts as a deterrent against content theft and a basic mechanism for proving prior ownership or existence of content at a given moment, adding a layer of verifiable provenance in a noisy digital world.\n\n<strong>Target Customers:</strong>\nFreelance journalists, independent bloggers, research paper authors, digital artists, anyone creating original digital content who wants a simple timestamped record linked to their name/handle.\n\n<strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope - Implement in a Day:</strong>\n\nThe goal is to build the absolute core function: linking content hash to identity and timestamp.\n\n1.  <strong>Simple Web Page:</strong> A single HTML page served by a minimal backend (like a tiny Node.js, Flask, or even a few lines of PHP).\n2.  <strong>Identity Input:</strong> A text field where the user types their name or a chosen handle. No complex login required for the MVP – self-declared identity is sufficient for the first day.\n3.  <strong>Content Input:</strong> A large text area where the user pastes their text content (e.g., a news draft, blog post, research note). A file upload is a stretch goal for day one, stick to text.\n4.  <strong>Attest Button:</strong> A button that, when clicked, triggers the process.\n5.  <strong>Hashing:</strong> Use a standard hashing algorithm available client-side or server-side (e.g., SHA-256). Calculate the hash of the content entered in the text area.\n6.  <strong>Timestamping:</strong> Get the current server-side timestamp (more reliable than client-side).\n7.  <strong>Record Creation:</strong> Store a simple record containing the user's handle, the content hash, and the timestamp. Store this in the simplest possible way: append it as a new line in a simple text file or JSON file on the server's filesystem. No database needed for day one.\n8.  <strong>User Feedback:</strong> Display the generated hash and timestamp to the user, confirming that the content has been attested with that specific ID at that time.\n9.  <strong>No complex features:</strong> No searching attested content, no public verification page, no user accounts (beyond the simple handle input), no AI analysis yet (that's the future). Just the core function of recording <code>(handle, hash, timestamp)</code>.\n\nThis MVP is focused on the backend creation of the attestation record, which is the core of proving origin. Future iterations can add richer identity verification, different content types, a public verification API, and AI features to analyze content provenance against attested records or assist in content analysis itself.\n\nGood luck building!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>