<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:09:17 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Unstick Your Pipeline: Find Dormant B2B Leads Fast]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=yfXEQmCjjviZVs6B6pBBJ271Xvvok_tppOKL1W1X7MRrsQnzqviGP8CxZhgmT-iC</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=yfXEQmCjjviZVs6B6pBBJ271Xvvok_tppOKL1W1X7MRrsQnzqviGP8CxZhgmT-iC</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2025 00:09:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-annual-idea-dont-let-leads-linger">The Annual Idea: Don't Let Leads Linger</h2>
<p>Indie hackers, greetings. It's that time of year again. Forget complex algorithms and massive datasets for a moment. Let's focus on a simple, painful problem in B2B sales that <em>you</em> can solve.</p>
<p><strong>The Idea: Lagging Lead Locator</strong></p>
<p>A dead-simple tool that helps B2B sales teams identify potential leads in their pipeline or CRM data that haven't received recent attention or contact.</p>
<p><strong>The Problem:</strong> Sales pipelines get messy. Leads are added, statuses change (or don't), and busy reps can easily lose track of promising opportunities simply because they haven't interacted with them recently. Valuable potential deals fall through the cracks.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong> Prevent revenue loss by ensuring valuable leads aren't forgotten. Provide sales teams with a quick, actionable list of leads that need immediate follow-up, increasing efficiency and conversion rates without requiring significant changes to their existing workflow.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong> Small to medium-sized B2B companies, particularly those using basic CRM systems, spreadsheets, or simply lacking robust workflow automation to manage their sales leads. Sales managers and individual reps frustrated by manual pipeline reviews.</p>
<p><strong>The MVP: Build This Today</strong></p>
<p>The magic is in the simplicity and speed of delivery. Your minimum viable product, runnable <em>today</em>, looks like this:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Input:</strong> A single webpage or command-line interface (CLI) where a user can upload a standard CSV file containing their lead data.</li>
<li><strong>Required Data:</strong> The CSV needs at least two columns: <code>Lead Identifier</code> (Name, ID, Email) and <code>Last Contact Date</code> (a date string in a predictable format, e.g., YYYY-MM-DD).</li>
<li><strong>Logic:</strong> The tool reads the CSV. It iterates through each row.</li>
<li><strong>Analysis:</strong> For each lead, it compares the <code>Last Contact Date</code> to the current date. If the difference is greater than a predefined threshold (make it a user input, default to 30 days), that lead is flagged.</li>
<li><strong>Output:</strong> Display a simple list or table showing the <code>Lead Identifier</code> for all flagged leads directly on the page or in the console.</li>
</ol>
<p>That's it. No database is required for the MVP. The processing is stateless upon file upload. You are building a filter based on a date comparison. This is fundamentally a data analytics task, identifying outliers based on a simple rule.</p>
<p><strong>Why This MVP?</strong></p>
<p>It solves a real problem instantly. It doesn't require integration with complex CRMs (yet). It works with the data small businesses likely already have (even in spreadsheets). It's constrained enough to build in a single day or a long evening.</p>
<p>Future iterations can add CRM integrations, more sophisticated criteria (based on status, lead score if available), simple reporting, perhaps even basic AI for predicting <em>which</em> lagging leads are most likely to convert based on historical data (if available). But start <em>today</em> with the simple filter.</p>
<p>Build this, share it. The B2B world needs simple tools that deliver immediate, tangible value.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>