<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 06:03:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Atomic Truths: A Pseudonymous AI-Augmented Fact Wiki]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=LgFSWPB1G4Y22aLL6afNTgxpm52ro3og602YmuidaI7IhVdOucel1bdXcA925LGo</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=LgFSWPB1G4Y22aLL6afNTgxpm52ro3og602YmuidaI7IhVdOucel1bdXcA925LGo</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 06:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="atomic-truths-a-pseudonymous-ai-augmented-fact-wiki">Atomic Truths: A Pseudonymous AI-Augmented Fact Wiki</h1>
<h2 id="brief-description">Brief Description</h2>
<p>Imagine a world where reliable, granular knowledge is instantly accessible and verifiably sourced. "Atomic Truths" is a decentralized platform where users contribute individual, concise "atomic facts" – single units of verifiable information. Each fact is attributed to a unique, persistent, pseudonymous digital identity, fostering trust and accountability without compromising privacy. The platform is engineered from the ground up for AI, which will eventually interconnect these facts, detect inconsistencies, and generate a dynamic, intelligent knowledge graph. This is not just a wiki; it's a living ledger of micro-truths, constantly refined by collective human intelligence and amplified by machine learning.</p>
<h2 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h2>
<p>"Atomic Truths" fundamentally redefines how we curate and access knowledge. It solves the pervasive problem of unreliable information by decentralizing contribution into verifiable, atomic units. By tying contributions to pseudonymous identities, it builds a reputation system based purely on the quality and accuracy of the facts provided, promoting higher fidelity knowledge than traditional, monolithic wiki pages. The system’s architecture uniquely positions it to harness advanced AI for automatic linking, semantic understanding, contradiction detection, and the creation of a truly intelligent, evolving knowledge base.</p>
<h2 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h2>
<p>This platform will resonate deeply with:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Researchers & Academics:</strong> Needing precise, attributable facts for their work.</li>
<li><strong>Fact-Checkers & Journalists:</strong> Seeking verifiable data points and their origins.</li>
<li><strong>Domain Experts:</strong> Individuals possessing highly specialized knowledge who want to contribute with precision and receive due (pseudonymous) credit.</li>
<li><strong>Educators & Students:</strong> Requiring high-fidelity, easily digestible information and sources.</li>
<li><strong>Knowledge-Intensive Communities:</strong> Any group that benefits from a shared, highly accurate, and dynamically updated base of specific information.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day)</h2>
<p>An indie developer can build a truly powerful foundation for "Atomic Truths" within a single day. The focus for this MVP is laying the groundwork for verifiable, granular knowledge capture and basic retrieval:</p>
<ol>
<li><p><strong>Frontend (Single Page Web Application):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Fact Submission Form:</strong> A clean interface with a large text area for the "Atomic Fact" (e.g., "The human heart has four chambers") and a smaller, optional text input for "Context/Source" (e.g., "Gray's Anatomy, Chapter 15").</li>
<li><strong>Fact List Display:</strong> A scrollable, reverse chronological list of all submitted facts, clearly showing the fact content, its context (if provided), and the contributor's pseudonymous ID.</li>
<li><strong>Basic Search Bar:</strong> A simple input field allowing real-time, client-side filtering of the displayed facts based on keywords (case-insensitive text matching).</li></ul></li>
<li><p><strong>Backend (Minimal API & Storage):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>API Endpoints:</strong> A single <code>POST /facts</code> endpoint to receive and store new fact submissions, and a <code>GET /facts</code> endpoint to retrieve all stored facts. Focus on simplicity and speed.</li>
<li><strong>Data Storage:</strong> A single-file, local database like SQLite. The schema needs just one table: <code>facts (id INTEGER PRIMARY KEY, content TEXT NOT NULL, context TEXT, contributor_id TEXT NOT NULL, created_at DATETIME DEFAULT CURRENT_TIMESTAMP)</code>. Efficient indexing on <code>contributor_id</code> and <code>content</code> for future scalability is advisable.</li></ul></li>
<li><p><strong>Digital Identity (Pseudonymous & Persistent):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Client-Side ID Generation:</strong> On a user's first visit, generate a unique, random, persistent string (e.g., a simple UUID like <code>guest_7a1b3f-c2d9-4e0a</code>) and store it securely in a browser cookie or LocalStorage. This will be their pseudonymous "contributor ID."</li>
<li><strong>Automated Attribution:</strong> This generated ID is automatically sent with every fact submission and stored in the database, linking contributions to a unique, non-real-world identity.</li></ul></li>
<li><p><strong>AI (Initial Hint & Future-Proofing):</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>For this MVP, the "AI" is primarily conceptual and foundational. The database design, focusing on atomic facts, inherently prepares the system for advanced AI integration.</li>
<li>**</li></ul></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>