<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:03:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: AI Schema Inferencer: Structure from Examples]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=sDyk691Jw2mJ32MggYDIlg_xFOFy2-1mDsTnHNcWruODfRdCr6Ab0vBcUeA_KIMw</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=sDyk691Jw2mJ32MggYDIlg_xFOFy2-1mDsTnHNcWruODfRdCr6Ab0vBcUeA_KIMw</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 12:03:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ai-schema-inferencer-structure-from-examples">AI Schema Inferencer: Structure from Examples</h2>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong><br />
A web utility that automatically generates data schemas (like JSON Schema) from examples of structured data provided by the user, leveraging AI.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong><br />
Simplifies and accelerates the process of defining data structures for APIs, databases, validation, and documentation by inferring schemas directly from sample data, reducing manual work and potential errors.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong><br />
Software developers, data engineers, API designers, technical writers, anyone who needs to define or understand data structures.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a day):</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Single Page App:</strong> A minimal HTML page with two large <code>&lt;textarea&gt;</code> elements and a button.</li>
<li><strong>Input Area:</strong> The top text area is where the user pastes sample data examples (e.g., a JSON array <code>[{}, {}, ...]</code> or multiple line-delimited JSON objects).</li>
<li><strong>Processing Button:</strong> A button labeled, for instance, "Generate Schema".</li>
<li><strong>AI Integration:</strong> Client-side JavaScript or a simple serverless function takes the input text from the top text area, formats it into a prompt (e.g., "Infer the JSON Schema for the following data examples:\n\n<code>json\n[Pasted Data]\n</code>\n\nProvide only the JSON Schema, nothing else."), and sends an API request to a chosen AI model (like OpenAI's GPT or Anthropic's Claude).</li>
<li><strong>Output Area:</strong> The bottom text area is read-only and displays the raw text response received from the AI API after the request completes.</li>
</ol>
<p><strong>Focus:</strong> The critical part for the 1-day MVP is successfully getting the raw AI response that <em>attempts</em> to be a JSON Schema based on the input examples. Polish, input/output format validation, handling edge cases, multiple schema formats (e.g., YAML), and a more robust UI are all valuable additions for v2+.</p>
<hr />
<p><em>This idea sits at the intersection of AI, structured data processing, and developer utilities.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>