<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:09:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: AI-Curated Chronologies: The "Flashback Fact-Checker" for Indie Journalism]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=gugPg8EoGpM6whzPqzAmBmE5fifrTEzLWvAF9EgSvwXrRkMOWiuBXxwMHbUgmQDj</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=gugPg8EoGpM6whzPqzAmBmE5fifrTEzLWvAF9EgSvwXrRkMOWiuBXxwMHbUgmQDj</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:09:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The digital age has overwhelmed us with information, yet a critical need persists: quick, reliable, and contextually rich historical data. Indie journalists, researchers, and content creators often spend disproportionate time piecing together factual timelines and identifying key actors and events from a cacophony of sources. This problem intensifies when dealing with evolving stories, where maintaining an accurate, cross-referenced internal wiki becomes a monumental task. This year's idea tackles this head-on.</p>
<p><strong>Brief description of the idea</strong></p>
<p>We envision an AI-powered "Flashback Fact-Checker" – a micro-service that transforms raw, unstructured news articles or textual reports into structured, wiki-like chronological narratives. It’s a tool for rapid knowledge base construction, focusing on extracting, linking, and contextualizing factual information to build dynamic, verifiable historical accounts around specific topics, people, or events. Think of it as your personal, always-updating, AI-curated reference library for journalistic inquiries.</p>
<p><strong>Core value proposition</strong></p>
<p>This tool dramatically accelerates the research and fact-checking process for content creators. By instantly synthesizing disparate articles into a coherent, cross-referenced timeline of events and entities, it empowers users to quickly grasp the full context of a story, identify historical connections, and ensure factual accuracy, ultimately saving countless hours and enhancing reporting depth. It turns information overload into structured insight.</p>
<p><strong>Target customers</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Independent Journalists & Investigative Reporters:</strong> Those who need to build comprehensive backstories and verify facts across multiple sources efficiently.</li>
<li><strong>Small Newsrooms & Bloggers:</strong> Teams operating with limited resources who need to maintain an internal, easily updatable knowledge base.</li>
<li><strong>Academic Researchers & Analysts:</strong> Individuals who frequently synthesize information from numerous papers or reports to establish context or identify trends.</li>
<li><strong>Content Creators & Podcasters:</strong> Anyone producing fact-heavy content requiring meticulous research and chronological accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Minimum viable product (MVP) scope which can be implemented in a day</strong></p>
<p>Build a dead-simple web interface with:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Input Field:</strong> A prominent text area where a user can paste the URL of a single news article or a block of raw text.</li>
<li><strong>AI Processing:</strong> On submission, a serverless function (e.g., Vercel, Netlify Functions, Cloudflare Workers) takes the input, extracts the core text, and immediately sends it to an OpenAI GPT API (or similar LLM, like Anthropic's Claude or Google's Gemini).</li>
<li><strong>Prompt Engineering:</strong> The LLM is given a specific prompt: "From the following text, extract the main entities (people, organizations, locations), key events, and their chronological order. Format the output as a Markdown list with brief descriptions and any identified relationships."</li>
<li><strong>Output Display:</strong> The LLM's response is displayed directly below the input field in a readable format (e.g., Markdown rendered as HTML). Users can then copy this structured output.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>Key for "in a day": Focus purely on the input -> AI call -> display loop. No database, no user accounts, no editing features. Just the core synthesis engine.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>