<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:03:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Context-API: Your Proactive Personal Data Endpoint]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=0fEAIiIFUnZ7SiH05fMT4d7PED_lCR2t69ETEk-epGz69ZwiKuiRzJGGIY0d866R</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=0fEAIiIFUnZ7SiH05fMT4d7PED_lCR2t69ETEk-epGz69ZwiKuiRzJGGIY0d866R</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 18:03:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="brief-description">Brief Description</h3>
<p>"Context-API" is a lightweight, local daemon that transforms your immediate digital context into instantaneously accessible micro-APIs. Unlike traditional APIs you pull from, Context-API proactively observes a specific, user-approved slice of your local digital activity (e.g., a watched file directory, the active tab in a browser, or a selected text snippet) and makes it programmatically available via a simple, triggerable "personal endpoint." Think of it as an intelligent agent always ready to serve <em>your</em> most current, relevant data without you needing to manually export, copy, or search.</p>
<h3 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h3>
<p>It minimizes friction and cognitive load by turning implicit user context into explicit, consumable data. Context-API empowers users to quickly capture, reference, or inject their live digital state into other tools, scripts, or workflows with a single, intuitive action. This shifts the interaction paradigm from laborious data retrieval to immediate, context-aware data availability, fostering seamless automation and accelerated productivity.</p>
<h3 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h3>
<p>Indie developers, researchers, content creators, writers, data analysts, and knowledge workers who frequently navigate between applications and need quick access to "what they just saw" or "what they are currently working on." Anyone valuing speed, automation, and effortless context switching without leaving their workflow.</p>
<h3 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-can-be-implemented-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Can be implemented in a day)</h3>
<p>The one-day MVP is ruthlessly focused on demonstrating the core "proactive personal API" concept with minimal complexity.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Watched Context:</strong> A single local directory, pre-defined by the developer, e.g., <code>~/Documents/CurrentProject/</code>.</li>
<li><strong>Observation:</strong> A simple script (e.g., Python <code>watchdog</code> or polling <code>os.stat</code> in a loop) that continuously monitors this directory for <em>the most recently modified text file</em> (e.g., <code>.txt</code>, <code>.md</code>, <code>.log</code>). The "AI" is the real-time identification of this most relevant file.</li>
<li><strong>"API" Endpoint:</strong> Not an HTTP API, but a console output or clipboard interaction. The "API" is the <em>actionable access</em> to the context.</li>
<li><strong>HCI Paradigm (Trigger):</strong> A simple hotkey (e.g., <code>Ctrl+Alt+C</code>) that triggers the script to immediately read the identified "most recently modified file."</li>
<li><strong>Output:</strong> When the hotkey is pressed, the script copies the <em>full path and the first 500 characters</em> of the most recently modified text file in the watched directory to the user's clipboard. No GUI, no configuration UI – configuration is hardcoded in the script.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>