<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 06:03:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: The Personal Carbon Diet Nudger]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=78Ih-i1ltmMTiAq8IcAaKb0u6Oimmoxmv3t9s76ZRcc1ZXdcHl5o9aoqk_hfVKLH</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=78Ih-i1ltmMTiAq8IcAaKb0u6Oimmoxmv3t9s76ZRcc1ZXdcHl5o9aoqk_hfVKLH</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 06:03:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-personal-carbon-diet-nudger">The Personal Carbon Diet Nudger</h1>
<p>It's that time of year again. Let's cut straight to it. Here's a simple idea marrying AI, Sustainability, and Nudging, specifically designed with the indie developer's capacity for rapid prototyping in mind.</p>
<h2 id="brief-description">Brief Description</h2>
<p>A tool (web app, micro-service, or potentially a simple API) that helps individuals understand the environmental impact of their dietary choices and gently nudges them towards more sustainable options. The core idea is to provide instant feedback on common food items and offer small, actionable suggestions for reducing one's 'foodprint'.</p>
<h2 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h2>
<p>Making sustainable eating accessible and actionable. Users gain awareness of the carbon cost of their meals and receive personalized, non-judgmental suggestions for low-impact alternatives, empowering them to make planet-friendlier choices without drastic lifestyle overhauls.</p>
<h2 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h2>
<p>Environmentally conscious individuals curious about their personal impact; people exploring plant-based or reduced-meat diets; organizations promoting sustainable living among their members or employees.</p>
<h2 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope---implement-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope - Implement in a Day</h2>
<p>Focus on a <em>single input</em> and <em>static output</em>.</p>
<p>Create a basic web page with a simple input field labeled</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>