<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 12:03:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Personal Health Query Assistant: An AI-Powered Health Wiki MVP]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=U4UEE8MfzcBWzx5MyHZxDaoiUM5m4P-gMaQdbqZA9kNXo1-uzAE5cWjIxV3X0ZFf</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=U4UEE8MfzcBWzx5MyHZxDaoiUM5m4P-gMaQdbqZA9kNXo1-uzAE5cWjIxV3X0ZFf</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 12:03:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Listen up.</p>
<p>Many people struggle to keep track of their health information. Doctor visits, medications, symptoms, tests – it's fragmented and often inaccessible when needed most. Traditional health records are siloed, and personal notes are messy.</p>
<p><strong>The Idea:</strong> Build a simple, AI-powered personal health wiki.</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong> A tool where individuals can log health-related events and notes in plain text. An integrated AI agent processes these notes to help the user extract value, initially by suggesting potential questions they might want to ask their doctor based on their input history.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong> Empowers individuals to maintain a centralized, searchable record of their health journey and leverages AI to transform scattered notes into actionable insights, improving preparedness for medical consultations.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong> Individuals managing chronic conditions, caregivers tracking health for dependents, health-conscious people who want better personal health data organization, anyone who feels overwhelmed by keeping track of medical information.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope - Implementable in a Day:</strong></p>
<p>This needs to be sharp, focused, and achievable <em>today</em>.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Simple Interface:</strong> A single web page or desktop window with:<ul>
<li>A large text area for the user to paste or type notes (e.g., "Visited Dr. Smith today, mentioned persistent cough, was prescribed Z-Pak. Also noted fatigue.").</li>
<li>A "Add Note and Suggest Questions" button.</li>
<li>A display area below to show the history of notes added.</li>
<li>A small area to display the AI-suggested questions.</li></ul></li>
<li><strong>Data Storage:</strong> Store each user note as a simple timestamped entry in a flat file (like a newline-delimited JSON file or even just appended text file) or a local database (like SQLite) – just one table <code>notes (timestamp, content)</code>.</li>
<li><strong>AI Integration:</strong> Hook up a single API call to a large language model (e.g., OpenAI's GPT-4 or similar) when the button is clicked.<ul>
<li>The prompt to the AI API is crucial. It should be something like: "Based on the following health note(s), what is ONE insightful question this person might consider asking a medical professional? Keep it concise. [Insert latest user note or maybe last few notes here]."</li>
<li>Display the AI's single response below the input area.</li></ul></li>
<li><strong>History Display:</strong> Simply list the timestamp and content of previously added notes below the current input area, in reverse chronological order.</li>
</ol>
<p>That's it. Input a note, store it, call AI for ONE question based on that note (or recent notes), display note history and the single AI suggestion. No user accounts, no fancy formatting, no searching, no editing old notes, no multiple question suggestions, no linking, no advanced analysis. Just the core loop. Build this today.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>