<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:09:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: GitFlow Growth: Visualizing & Gamifying Your Dev Journey]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=Y1g_VAwrE_U52GGhkW71wKxw75VXQnthit-hjiqLC6sHNIkGXkE8CedH1BRRwN4l</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=Y1g_VAwrE_U52GGhkW71wKxw75VXQnthit-hjiqLC6sHNIkGXkE8CedH1BRRwN4l</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 00:09:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="gitflow-growth-visualizing--gamifying-your-dev-journey">GitFlow Growth: Visualizing &amp; Gamifying Your Dev Journey</h2>
<p><strong>Brief description:</strong> A lightweight tool that plugs into your code repositories (starting with Git) to track and visualize your coding activity, applying simple gamification mechanics and eventually, AI-powered insights to help you understand, optimize, and stay motivated in your development process.</p>
<p><strong>Core value proposition:</strong> Turn the often-invisible progress of coding into clear, actionable visualizations and engaging challenges. Gain insights into your coding habits, identify productive patterns (or bottlenecks), and keep momentum with satisfying gamified rewards.</p>
<p><strong>Target customers:</strong> Solo indie developers, freelancers, small developer teams, students, and anyone who wants to gain better visibility and motivation around their personal coding output.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum viable product (MVP) scope (implementable in a day):</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Git Repo Input:</strong> Provide a simple interface (CLI command or a single input field in a web/desktop app) to accept the local file path of a Git repository.</li>
<li><strong>Commit Count (7-Day):</strong> Read the commit history for the default branch (<code>main</code> or <code>master</code>) of the provided repository for the last 7 days.</li>
<li><strong>Display Raw Daily Count:</strong> Output a simple, unformatted text list showing the count of commits for each of the last 7 days (e.g., "Day -6: 3 commits, Day -5: 7 commits, … Day 0: 5 commits").</li>
</ol>
<p>This minimal scope validates the core functionality: connecting to a Git repo and extracting dated commit data, which is the absolute foundation for all future visualization, gamification, and analysis features. No charts, points, or AI needed for this initial validation step.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>