<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 12:03:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: AI-Lite Guardian: Your Indie Cybersecurity Co-Pilot]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=tAKoKiSNWGAfODbw8V8BtQRbARg9qtWihzgHJJ0shHVxIokTnbLzRvpLQuR-ywNT</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=tAKoKiSNWGAfODbw8V8BtQRbARg9qtWihzgHJJ0shHVxIokTnbLzRvpLQuR-ywNT</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 12:03:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="ai-lite-guardian-your-indie-cybersecurity-co-pilot">AI-Lite Guardian: Your Indie Cybersecurity Co-Pilot</h2>
<h4 id="brief-description-of-the-idea">Brief Description of the Idea</h4>
<p>Many small to medium businesses (SMBs) are vulnerable because enterprise-grade cybersecurity solutions are too complex and expensive. AI-Lite Guardian is a hyper-focused, lightweight anomaly detection engine designed to monitor critical system logs for suspicious activity. It provides early warnings to SMBs, allowing them to proactively address potential breaches before they escalate. It's about bringing "predictive cybersecurity" to the masses, simplified, allowing even a single server or application to have dedicated, intelligent threat monitoring.</p>
<h4 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h4>
<p>Deliver proactive, automated, and affordable cybersecurity anomaly detection. Reduce risk for SMBs by instantly identifying and alerting on unusual login patterns or system access, bridging the gap between basic firewall rules and complex SIEMs. Empower non-security experts with actionable intelligence, providing peace of mind through early threat prediction without the overhead.</p>
<h4 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h4>
<p>Small to medium businesses (SMBs), independent consultants, digital agencies, non-profits, and web hosts who need foundational security monitoring but lack dedicated IT security teams or large budgets. Also, Managed Service Providers (MSPs) looking to add focused, high-value security services to their offerings without significant overhead or deep cybersecurity expertise from their own team.</p>
<h4 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day)</h4>
<p>For an indie developer, the key is extreme focus to deliver immediate, tangible value. The goal is to build a hyper-specific anomaly detector for one high-value target:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Focus:</strong> Monitoring SSH authentication logs (<code>/var/log/auth.log</code> on Linux servers) – a high-value target for initial attack attempts and unauthorized access.</li>
<li><strong>Mechanism:</strong> A single Python script (or Go/Node.js, depending on your expertise) that:<ol>
<li><strong>Reads Logs:</strong> Continuously <code>tail</code>s or watches <code>/var/log/auth.log</code> for new entries in real-time.</li>
<li><strong>Parses Events:</strong> Extracts critical details such as login attempt success/failure status, usernames, and source IP addresses from each relevant log line.</li>
<li><strong>Anomaly Detection - Brute Force Prediction:</strong> Implements a simple, in-memory sliding window counter. If a specific IP address attempts <code>X</code> failed SSH logins within <code>Y</code> seconds (e.g., 5 failures in 60 seconds from the same IP), the script immediately flags this as a predictive brute-force attempt.</li>
<li><strong>Anomaly Detection - New Login Source Prediction:</strong> Maintains a minimal, local, persistent file (e.g., a simple JSON array or plaintext list) of</li></ol></li>
</ul>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>