<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 06:03:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: The One-Day API: AI Food Filter]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=1ssjCJ3SmohwNlsx7OTrNPFYaQs7tMGO2o5dlh49--LAoMDT9ZyCwzRI5ttcE6Cq</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=1ssjCJ3SmohwNlsx7OTrNPFYaQs7tMGO2o5dlh49--LAoMDT9ZyCwzRI5ttcE6Cq</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 06:03:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="annual-indie-dev-idea-ai-powered-recipe-filtering-api">Annual Indie Dev Idea: AI-Powered Recipe Filtering API</h1>
<p>Alright developers, it's that time of year. No lengthy intros. The world is hungry, both literally and for smarter software. This year, the confluence of AI, the API economy, and the evergreen domain of food presents a clear opportunity.</p>
<p>The explosion of recipe content online is overwhelming. Users need help cutting through the noise to find meals that fit their specific needs – dietary restrictions, allergies, available ingredients, cooking time, and more. Existing solutions are often clunky, rely on manual tagging, or are siloed within specific apps.</p>
<p>An AI-powered API in this space can become a crucial building block for the next generation of food and health applications.</p>
<h2 id="brief-description">Brief Description</h2>
<p>A simple API that accepts user constraints (like dietary needs, allergies, disliked ingredients, available ingredients) and returns relevant recipe suggestions or filtered recipe lists.</p>
<h2 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h2>
<p>For developers: Easily integrate sophisticated, constraint-aware recipe discovery into their apps (meal planners, grocery list builders, cooking assistants, health trackers) without needing to build complex filtering logic or large recipe databases themselves. Focus on the user experience; delegate the recipe finding complexity.</p>
<p>For end-users (via developer apps): Quickly find meal ideas that are <em>actually</em> suitable for their specific situation, reducing waste and decision fatigue.</p>
<h2 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h2>
<p>Indie developers and small teams building mobile apps, web applications, or services in the food, health, wellness, fitness, and smart home/kitchen domains.</p>
<h2 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day)</h2>
<p>The goal is to demonstrate the <em>API concept</em> and basic filtering. Forget complex AI models for day one. Here’s the core:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>A simple web service:</strong> Use a lightweight framework (Flask/Python, Express/Node.js, or similar) to set up a basic HTTP server.</li>
<li><strong>One API Endpoint:</strong> Create a single <code>POST</code> endpoint, e.g., <code>/suggest-recipe</code> or <code>/find-recipes</code>.</li>
<li><strong>Accept Input:</strong> This endpoint should accept JSON input containing a few key parameters. For a day-one MVP, let's focus on <code>dietary_needs</code> (string, e.g., "vegetarian, gluten-free") and <code>available_ingredients</code> (list of strings, e.g., ["chicken breast", "broccoli", "rice"]).</li>
<li><strong>Basic Data Store:</strong> Hardcode a small list (5-10) of extremely simple, generic recipes within your code. Each recipe should have a title, a brief description/steps, and associated tags (e.g., "vegetarian", "vegan", "gluten-free", "contains_nuts") and a list of its core ingredients.</li>
<li><strong>Simple Logic (The "AI" for Day 1):</strong> Implement basic filtering logic.<ul>
<li>Check if the <code>dietary_needs</code> tags are present in the recipe's tags (e.g., if "vegetarian" is required, only return recipes tagged "vegetarian"). Exclude recipes with allergy tags if specified in <code>dietary_needs</code>.</li>
<li><em>Crucially</em>, for ingredient filtering, implement a simple check: Return recipes where, say, <em>at least 3</em> of the recipe's ingredients are present in the <code>available_ingredients</code> list <em>or</em> the main ingredient matches if the recipe has a prominent one. Keep this logic extremely basic.</li></ul></li>
<li><strong>Return Output:</strong> The API returns a JSON response containing <em>one</em> recipe object from your hardcoded list that matches the (minimal) criteria, or a</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>