<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:04:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: PlainSight: Your AI-Powered Textual Cognition Augmenter]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=QQN7fFkyLdEoiKXT02Q_5_tOWvkI_FtY15wITbtPkttzloA2R4i18sMNfAfDHPVw</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=QQN7fFkyLdEoiKXT02Q_5_tOWvkI_FtY15wITbtPkttzloA2R4i18sMNfAfDHPVw</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 12:04:38 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="brief-description-of-the-idea">Brief Description of the Idea</h3>
<p>PlainSight is a local-first application designed to transform your disparate plain text notes, articles, and documents into an effortlessly searchable and intelligently cross-referenced knowledge graph, powered by AI. Imagine a minimalist, text-focused interface that acts as an extension of your own memory, helping you recall, connect, and synthesize information from your accumulated knowledge without ever needing to leave your preferred plain text environment. It’s an external brain for your plain text universe, providing instant semantic recall and surfacing hidden connections.</p>
<h3 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h3>
<p>Stop losing track of your own insights, forgotten links, or crucial details buried in your text files. PlainSight helps you leverage your accumulated knowledge more effectively by providing instant, context-aware recall and intelligent connections across all your plain text data. By offloading the cognitive burden of remembering exactly <em>where</em> a piece of information resides or <em>how</em> it relates to another, it significantly boosts your creative synthesis and decision-making processes, empowering you to think and create with less friction.</p>
<h3 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h3>
<ul>
<li><strong>Knowledge Workers:</strong> Academics, researchers, consultants, and analysts who rely heavily on text notes, papers, and reports. They need to quickly surface information and connect ideas across a vast personal corpus.</li>
<li><strong>Indie Hackers & Developers:</strong> Those who document everything in markdown or plain text, from project notes and code snippets to design philosophies and business ideas, and need a smarter way to navigate their intellectual output.</li>
<li><strong>Writers, Journalists, & Content Creators:</strong> Professionals needing quick, intelligent access to their accumulated ideas, research, drafts, and character notes to maintain consistency and accelerate creation.</li>
<li><strong>Life-long Learners:</strong> Anyone overwhelmed by information overload who seeks to build a personal, augmentable knowledge base from their reading and thinking.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day)</h3>
<p>An indie developer can build a powerful initial version of PlainSight within a single day, leveraging existing AI APIs and focusing on core functionality.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Folder Monitoring & Ingestion:</strong> The application starts by allowing the user to specify a local folder (or multiple folders). It recursively reads all <code>*.txt</code> and <code>*.md</code> files within these directories.</li>
<li><strong>Simple Chunking & Embedding:</strong> For each file, the content is broken down into smaller, manageable "chunks" (e.g., by paragraph or fixed character count). Each chunk is then sent to an OpenAI Embedding API (e.g., <code>text-embedding-3-small</code>) to generate a vector embedding, representing its semantic meaning. These embeddings, along with references to their source file and original text, are stored in memory or a simple local key-value store.</li>
<li><strong>Command-Line Interface (CLI):</strong> A minimalist command-line interface provides the core user interaction. The user types a natural language query into the CLI.</li>
<li><strong>AI-Powered Semantic Retrieval:</strong> When a query is entered, its embedding is generated. This query embedding is then compared against all stored chunk embeddings using cosine similarity to find the top 5-10 most semantically relevant text chunks from the user's plain text library.</li>
<li><strong>Contextualized AI Response:</strong> The retrieved chunks are then compiled and sent along with the original user query to a powerful LLM API (e.g., OpenAI's <code>gpt-3.5-turbo</code>). The prompt instructs the LLM to synthesize an answer based <em>only</em> on the provided context, explaining its reasoning or directly quoting the most relevant sections.</li>
<li><strong>Plain Text Output with Source Links:</strong> The LLM's synthesized response is printed directly to the console in plain text, ideally including references (filename, line number) to the original source documents where the information was found.</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>