<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:03:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Secure Your Stories: AI-Powered Shield for Journalists]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=0ufuWwgE-gRke9fzU43T-1WXvh6t9ID2gQcuPPnBrLl_wVXpdTVNdfQQum4R_8cm</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=0ufuWwgE-gRke9fzU43T-1WXvh6t9ID2gQcuPPnBrLl_wVXpdTVNdfQQum4R_8cm</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Alright indie developers, annual idea drop. No fluff, just opportunity.</p>
<p>The world needs reliable journalism more than ever, but digital threats loom large. Journalists are increasingly targets, and protecting their sources is paramount. Traditional newsrooms have resources; independent and freelance journalists often don't. This gap is where you come in.</p>
<h3 id="brief-description-of-the-idea">Brief Description of the Idea</h3>
<p>Build an AI-powered tool that helps journalists scan their drafts (or published articles) for unintentional security and privacy risks. Think of it as a spell checker, but for cybersecurity and source protection. It would identify potentially sensitive information like inadvertently included contact details, identifiable metadata in images, or links that could compromise security.</p>
<h3 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h3>
<p>Empower journalists to publish safely and protect their sources' anonymity in the digital age. Provide peace of mind and a critical layer of digital defense to those on the front lines of reporting, especially independent operators who lack dedicated security teams.</p>
<h3 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h3>
<p>Freelance journalists, investigative reporters, small independent news blogs and publications, academic researchers handling sensitive data for public dissemination.</p>
<h3 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope: Implementable in a Day</h3>
<p>Forget complex AI models for day one. The core value can be demonstrated with simple string matching and pattern recognition.</p>
<p><strong>MVP:</strong> A simple web page with a text area. The journalist pastes their article text. On submission, your backend runs a few basic checks:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Email Address Scanner:</strong> Simple regex to find patterns that look like email addresses (<code>\b[A-Za-z0-9._%+-]+@[A-Za-z0-9.-]+\.[A-Za-z]{2,}\b</code>). Flag these as potential risks.</li>
<li><strong>Phone Number Scanner:</strong> Basic regex for common phone number formats (e.g., <code>\b\d{3}[-.]?\d{3}[-.]?\d{4}\b</code>). Flag these.</li>
<li><strong>URL Checker:</strong> Extract URLs and perform a <em>very</em> basic check (e.g., does it use HTTP instead of HTTPS? Is it a known free URL shortener that might be misused? - <em>skip malicious check for MVP, too complex</em>). Flag non-HTTPS links.</li>
<li><strong>Keyword Spotting:</strong> Allow the user to input a few custom keywords or phrases they want to ensure are <em>not</em> in the final text (e.g., code names for sources, specific project identifiers). Simple string search for these.</li>
</ol>
<p>The output is a list of potential issues found and their locations (line number or surrounding text). No fancy UI, just plain text or a simple highlighted list. No account management, no document uploads (just paste text), no complex natural language processing.</p>
<p>This MVP simulates the <em>detection</em> aspect. It provides immediate, tangible value by catching obvious mistakes that could compromise security, all built with basic programming skills in under a day. The AI angle comes later as you replace regex with entity recognition, sensitive data models, and potentially analyzing structured data or metadata.</p>
<p>Build this. It's valuable, topical, and achievable. Go.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>