<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 12:03:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Proactive Meeting AI: Your Daily Pre-Meeting Intel Brief]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=ZUZogs5K-cUpfUQ1RPTcTPie4FLzyYHiCjBplxuUpokNNBQflWBzWniRZk7_6J38</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=ZUZogs5K-cUpfUQ1RPTcTPie4FLzyYHiCjBplxuUpokNNBQflWBzWniRZk7_6J38</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 12:03:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="proactive-meeting-ai-your-daily-pre-meeting-intel-brief">Proactive Meeting AI: Your Daily Pre-Meeting Intel Brief</h2>
<h3 id="brief-description-of-the-idea">Brief Description of the Idea</h3>
<p>Imagine waking up, glancing at your calendar, and instantly having a concise, AI-generated briefing for each of your upcoming meetings. This isn't just a calendar reminder; it's a smart assistant that anticipates discussion points, potential questions, and key takeaways for every scheduled interaction. It's about transforming meeting preparation from a reactive chore into a seamless, proactive advantage.</p>
<h3 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h3>
<p>This tool liberates knowledge workers from tedious meeting prep, significantly boosting individual and team productivity. By proactively delivering tailored insights and context, it ensures you enter every meeting informed, focused, and ready to contribute effectively. This translates to shorter, more productive meetings, better decision-making, and less time wasted on unproductive discussions.</p>
<h3 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h3>
<p>Our primary target customers are knowledge workers, consultants, project managers, sales professionals, and anyone who regularly attends multiple meetings. Small business owners and indie founders, often juggling many roles, will find immense value in automating this critical, yet time-consuming, aspect of their day.</p>
<h3 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day)</h3>
<p>The goal for a one-day MVP is to demonstrate the core value proposition with minimal overhead. For an indie developer, this means leveraging existing APIs and keeping the UI incredibly simple.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Google Calendar Integration (Read-Only):</strong> Users connect their Google Calendar via OAuth2. The application retrieves a list of the user's upcoming meetings (today and tomorrow). No complex data storage or user accounts required beyond the OAuth token for session.</li>
<li><strong>Basic Meeting List Display:</strong> A simple web page or desktop window lists the retrieved upcoming meetings, showing their title, time, and attendees.</li>
<li><strong>On-Demand AI Insight Generation:</strong> For each listed meeting, a "Generate Insights" button appears. When clicked, the application sends the meeting title and description (if available) to a large language model (LLM) API (e.g., OpenAI's GPT-3.5 Turbo or Claude 3 Haiku).</li>
<li><strong>Simple LLM Prompt:</strong> The prompt instructs the LLM to generate "3 potential discussion topics" or "3 key questions to consider" based <em>only</em> on the meeting title and description. Example prompt: "Based on a meeting titled 'Project Phoenix Alpha Review' with description 'Review progress, discuss roadblocks, plan next steps', list 3 potential discussion topics." </li>
<li><strong>Display Generated Insights:</strong> The AI-generated insights are displayed directly below the meeting entry on the simple UI. No saving, no sharing, just immediate, temporary display. </li>
</ol>
<p>This MVP proves the core concept: connecting your calendar, feeding simple data to an LLM, and getting instant, helpful insights back.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>