<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:02:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: The Edge AI Privacy Utility Play]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=RHVmDXhMSNM-iKw3NAvXA5Wh9VB8-cETXVKQXHpnbhwn389WKq905j5LktdLFu_1</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=RHVmDXhMSNM-iKw3NAvXA5Wh9VB8-cETXVKQXHpnbhwn389WKq905j5LktdLFu_1</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:02:57 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="local-privacy-sentinel">Local Privacy Sentinel</h1>
<p>This year's provocation is simple: leverage AI on the edge to build privacy-focused utilities.</p>
<h3 id="brief-description">Brief Description</h3>
<p>A utility application that scans local files (documents, images, etc.) <em>on the user's device</em> using lightweight, edge-optimized AI models or simple pattern matching to identify sensitive personal information (like passport numbers, bank details, email addresses, specific facial features in photos) without ever uploading data to the cloud. The application then provides tools for the user to manage, redact, or securely store this sensitive data locally.</p>
<h3 id="core-value-proposition">Core Value Proposition</h3>
<p>Empower individuals and small businesses to proactively discover and protect their sensitive digital footprint on their own devices, significantly reducing the risk of data leakage and enhancing personal privacy by keeping scanning and processing entirely local.</p>
<h3 id="target-customers">Target Customers</h3>
<p>Privacy-conscious individuals, freelancers, medical or legal professionals handling sensitive client data, small businesses managing employee or customer records, anyone looking for better control over their personal data sprawl.</p>
<h3 id="minimum-viable-product-mvp-scope-implementable-in-a-day">Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a day)</h3>
<p>The absolute core MVP for a day's work focuses on a single, specific task:</p>
<p>Build a command-line utility or a simple GUI app with one input field (directory path). This app should scan <code>.txt</code> files within the specified directory <em>and its subdirectories</em>. Using only a simple regex or a pre-compiled, ultra-lightweight local AI model (e.g., a tiny ONNX model under 1MB), identify potential email addresses. The output should be a simple list printed to the console or displayed in a listbox: File Path, Line Number, Found Email Pattern.</p>
<p>This focuses purely on <em>local scanning</em> and <em>identification</em> of a single, common data pattern in a single file type. No data modification, no complex UI, just the fundamental edge-based analysis and reporting.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>