<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:03:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: RecipeNet: AI-Powered Structured Food Data for Developers]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=m8gLXoeQq9phzdnQA5lL7bDItc2xm0IZ7IX4T8GoGJz99LvsJUMeVZnMrAXb0Oq7</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=m8gLXoeQq9phzdnQA5lL7bDItc2xm0IZ7IX4T8GoGJz99LvsJUMeVZnMrAXb0Oq7</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 06:03:58 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>RecipeNet is an AI-driven tool designed to bridge the gap between human-readable recipes and machine-actionable data. It takes free-form recipe text (or eventually, images) and transforms it into a clean, structured data format, making food content instantly usable for software applications. Imagine feeding it a blog post recipe and getting back perfect JSON-LD or API-ready data. This enables a new class of food-centric applications and automation for culinary content. For software developers, RecipeNet eliminates the tedious, error-prone manual parsing of recipe data, accelerating the development of food-related apps, meal planners, nutritional trackers, and e-commerce platforms. For content creators and businesses, it automates SEO enhancement, facilitates multi-platform content distribution, and enables sophisticated data analysis from their food content, unlocking new monetization and personalization opportunities with minimal engineering overhead. We envision RecipeNet as the foundational layer for the next generation of smart kitchens and personalized nutrition.Target customers include indie software developers and small teams building recipe management systems, dietary tracking apps, meal planning tools, or grocery list generators. Food bloggers, culinary content creators, and food media companies looking to automate structured data generation for SEO and API integrations will also benefit. Finally, startups and small businesses in the meal kit, food delivery, and smart kitchen appliance sectors needing a scalable way to process and standardize recipe data from diverse sources will find RecipeNet invaluable. For an MVP, we propose "RecipeNet Mini", a solution implementable within a day. The frontend will be a single web page with a large <code>textarea</code> for users to paste raw recipe text (e.g., "Mushroom Risotto: Ingredients - 1 cup Arborio rice, 4 cups vegetable broth… Instructions - Heat oil, add rice…"), a prominent "Convert to JSON" button, and a read-only <code>textarea</code> to display the generated JSON output. This MVP will have no complex styling or navigation, focusing purely on raw functionality. The backend will be a lightweight serverless function (e.g., AWS Lambda, Vercel Function, Cloudflare Worker) that receives the raw recipe text from the frontend. This function will then call an LLM API (e.g., OpenAI's GPT-3.5 Turbo) with a precisely crafted prompt. An example prompt would be: "You are an expert recipe parser. Extract the following information from the provided recipe text and return it as a JSON object. Ensure keys are 'title', 'ingredients' (list of strings), 'instructions' (list of strings), and 'notes' (string, optional). For ingredients, list each item separately. For instructions, list each step separately. If no specific title is given, infer one. If no notes, leave it empty. Recipe text: [USER_INPUT_RECIPE_TEXT]". The backend will return the LLM's JSON response directly to the frontend. This MVP leverages readily available AI APIs and focuses solely on the core value: transforming unstructured recipe text into structured JSON, making it truly achievable within a day for an experienced indie developer.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>