<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 18:03:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Your Next Indie AI/Predictive Idea: The Micro-SaaS Churn Alarm (One-Day MVP)]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=aCRFSmlIKy95uUFOdJEJudwf2_Ch94lEhEDjUiEokj2Z5f24wV5B9Ub42g-VMGkZ</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=aCRFSmlIKy95uUFOdJEJudwf2_Ch94lEhEDjUiEokj2Z5f24wV5B9Ub42g-VMGkZ</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 18:03:09 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-micro-saas-churn-alarm">The Micro-SaaS Churn Alarm</h3>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong><br />
Build a simple, focused tool that helps solo founders and small teams running subscription products (SaaS, newsletters, communities) proactively identify users who are likely to churn. It uses basic user activity data to flag 'at-risk' individuals, enabling founders to reach out before they lose the customer.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong><br />
Increase customer lifetime value (LTV) and reduce churn by giving founders an actionable, low-effort way to spot and re-engage disengaged users, without needing a full-blown analytics suite.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong><br />
Indie SaaS founders, newsletter creators with paid tiers, community operators running membership sites, course creators with subscription access. Anyone with recurring revenue and minimal user activity data.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day):</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Simple Web Interface:</strong> A single page with a form to upload a CSV file.</li>
<li><strong>CSV Input:</strong> The CSV should contain at least two columns: <code>user_id</code> (unique identifier) and <code>last_active_date</code> (date or timestamp of the user's last recorded activity). A threshold for "inactive" (e.g., 7 days) should be configurable or hardcoded initially.</li>
<li><strong>Processing Logic:</strong> On upload, the backend reads the CSV, calculates the number of days since the <code>last_active_date</code> for each user relative to today's date.</li>
<li><strong>Identify At-Risk:</strong> Any user whose 'days since last active' exceeds the defined threshold is marked as 'at-risk'.</li>
<li><strong>Display Results:</strong> Show a simple list or table on the same page (or a results page) listing the <code>user_id</code> and 'days since last active' for <em>only</em> the users identified as at-risk.</li>
<li><strong>No Database/Auth:</strong> No user accounts, no saving uploaded data long-term, no persistent database for this MVP. Just stateless processing of the uploaded file.</li>
</ol>
<p>This MVP delivers immediate value: a founder can upload their data each morning and get a prioritized list of customers to check in with, turning raw activity logs into actionable business intelligence within minutes. The "predictive" element is initially basic (days inactive) but forms the core for future, more sophisticated models (e.g., using other activity types, machine learning, trends) as the product evolves. Get this simple version out, see if founders find value in the <em>process</em> of identifying these users, and iterate from there. Good luck!</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>