<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:03:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: The Plain Text Productivity Bot: An AI + Cloud Micro-Service for Indie Hackers]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=5cvqESgfyJIXuZuNk1UTNjaf94pdIn0Qk1RyETML2I4uhPGXCuHYRm0GJT9BRt0e</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=5cvqESgfyJIXuZuNk1UTNjaf94pdIn0Qk1RyETML2I4uhPGXCuHYRm0GJT9BRt0e</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 06:03:34 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="the-plain-text-productivity-bot">The Plain Text Productivity Bot</h2>
<p>Alright indies, let's cut to it. Your superpower is shipping simple, focused tools that solve real problems. This year's theme – AI, Plain Text, Cloud – offers fertile ground. Forget complex applications; think elegant, atomic services that augment existing workflows. Here's one:</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong> A minimal, cloud-hosted service that takes structured or semi-structured plain text input and transforms it into a useful plain text output using AI. The simplest iteration is a "Meeting Notes Summarizer". You paste your raw meeting notes (like bullet points, transcribed speech with timestamps, etc.), and the bot returns a clean, plain text summary focusing on decisions and action items.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong> Leverages the power of modern AI for a single, high-value task, delivered via a simple, plain text interface. It integrates frictionlessly into any plain text-based workflow (editors, notes apps, terminals) without requiring new habits or complex software. Speed, simplicity, and focused intelligence.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong> Anyone who takes notes in plain text during meetings, calls, or lectures. This includes developers, writers, researchers, project managers, students, and generally productivity-focused individuals who value efficiency and minimal tool chains.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope - Implementable in a day:</strong></p>
<p>The goal is to prove the core loop: receive text -&gt; process with AI in the cloud -&gt; return text.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Choose Your Cloud Function:</strong> Pick a serverless platform you know (AWS Lambda, Cloudflare Workers, Vercel Functions, etc.). This handles hosting and scaling the minuscule compute needed.</li>
<li><strong>Set Up an Endpoint:</strong> Create a simple HTTP endpoint (or a basic web page with a text area). This is your plain text ingress.</li>
<li><strong>Integrate AI API:</strong> Get an API key for a suitable model (e.g., OpenAI's GPT-4o mini, Anthropic's Haiku). Write the ~10 lines of code to call the API.</li>
<li><strong>Craft the Prompt:</strong> Design a simple, effective plain text prompt instructing the AI model. Example: `"Summarize the following meeting notes, extracting key decisions and action items only. Format the output as a simple bulleted list in plain text:</li>
</ol>
<p>[PASTE_USER_INPUT_HERE]"`</p>
<ol start="5">
<li><strong>Return Plain Text:</strong> The function receives the AI response, extracts the plain text summary, and returns it directly via the HTTP response or displays it on the simple web page.</li>
</ol>
<p>That's it. A plain text input, an AI brain in the cloud, and a plain text output. No databases, no fancy UIs, no user accounts initially. Build this core loop <em>today</em>. Ship it. See who uses it. The plain text interface makes it incredibly versatile; users can pipe notes from anywhere. This isn't about building a note-taking app; it's about building a micro-service that enhances plain text.</p>
<p>The possibilities for other plain text transformations are endless once this core is built: Plain text outline -&gt; Plain text draft paragraph, Plain text data list -&gt; Plain text formatted report, Plain text commit message draft -&gt; Plain text improved commit message. Start with one, make it perfect.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>