<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:23:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Low-Code AI-Powered IoT Data Visualizer MVP]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=UU7fEV5r4u_jRik5G8JjnLvQBjsWJ9HMP_ms7FtVEG5-p78iTLq4oknayf1fZQ2h</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=UU7fEV5r4u_jRik5G8JjnLvQBjsWJ9HMP_ms7FtVEG5-p78iTLq4oknayf1fZQ2h</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:23:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1 id="low-code-ai-powered-iot-data-visualizer">Low-Code AI-Powered IoT Data Visualizer</h1>
<p>This year's idea combines AI, IoT, and Low-code to address a common challenge: quickly seeing and understanding data from connected devices without getting bogged down in complex programming.</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong> Build a web tool where users can input an IoT data source (like an MQTT topic or a simple HTTP endpoint returning JSON), and the tool automatically visualizes the incoming data with minimal or no configuration. An AI component suggests or automatically selects the best visualization type.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong> Empower small businesses, researchers, and hobbyists to easily visualize real-time IoT data streams without writing code or setting up complex dashboards. Instant insight from their connected devices.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong> Individuals and small organizations using IoT devices who lack the time or technical expertise to build custom data dashboards. Examples include small-scale agriculture (sensor data), local environmental monitoring, home automation enthusiasts with custom sensors, or R&amp;D teams needing quick data checks.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a day):</strong></p>
<p>The goal is a hyper-focused prototype demonstrating the core loop: Connect -&gt; Visualize Automatically.</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Data Source Input:</strong> A simple web form with one input field: a URL or topic string (e.g., <code>mqtt://broker.example.com/sensor/temperature</code> or <code>http://api.example.com/data</code>). Choose ONE protocol/format to support initially (e.g., Public MQTT broker or a simple JSON endpoint returning `{"value": 25.5}).</li>
<li><strong>Data Listener:</strong> A tiny backend service (e.g., Node.js with <code>mqtt</code> or Python with <code>requests</code> and a microframework like Flask/FastAPI) that connects to the specified data source upon form submission.</li>
<li><strong>Automatic Data Type Detection & Simplistic AI Suggestion:</strong> The backend reads the incoming data payload. Based on its structure (e.g., a single number, a string), it makes a <em>hardcoded</em></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Food for Thought: On the Biology of 'Ought']]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=6S2hGDPggsKELwfvYg6ltYHC83QkowHOB7vYJj1FiR-yeh8pcdm-FpFSnd68zTDc</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=6S2hGDPggsKELwfvYg6ltYHC83QkowHOB7vYJj1FiR-yeh8pcdm-FpFSnd68zTDc</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 14:23:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Consider the small signals deep within the brain that help us weigh options, assign value, and steer towards one path instead of another. Neuroscience is lifting the veil on these processes – the roots of choice, both economic and personal, maybe even moral.</p>
<p>For a long time, economics has modelled human action based on revealed preference or assumed rationality, while moral philosophy has debated duties, virtues, and consequences as guides for action.</p>
<p>Now, we see glimpses of the biological engine beneath it all.</p>
<p>How does seeing this engine, this substrate of our choices and values, alter our questions about responsibility, fairness, or the very meaning of a 'good' life or a 'right' decision? Does understanding the mechanics of 'is' change the landscape of 'ought'?</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>