<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:09:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: EcoCompute AI: Pinpoint & Prune Idle AI Cloud Costs]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=jfsA7MIBYVYoPB0fN26lNh3-WowwKa6CHS6v7uqX3k8fJgI6UKSL62LzpiAUHIDQ</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=jfsA7MIBYVYoPB0fN26lNh3-WowwKa6CHS6v7uqX3k8fJgI6UKSL62LzpiAUHIDQ</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2025 00:09:06 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The era of AI is upon us, but it comes with a silent, significant cost: ever-ballooning cloud bills and a growing carbon footprint from inefficient compute. Training and inference for AI models devour resources, often leaving behind forgotten, idle, yet still-billing instances. This is where you, the agile indie developer, come in.</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description of the Idea:</strong> Create 'EcoCompute AI,' a minimalist tool that helps developers and small teams identify and eliminate wasted cloud spend associated with idle or underutilized AI/ML compute resources. It translates complex cloud metrics into clear, actionable insights for both cost savings and environmental impact reduction.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong> 'Save substantial money and reduce your carbon footprint by intelligently identifying and acting on underutilized AI/ML cloud infrastructure.'</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong> Individual data scientists, ML engineers, small AI/ML focused startups, and development teams within larger organizations that manage their own cloud infrastructure on AWS, GCP, or Azure and are acutely aware of their monthly cloud spend.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope for Day One:</strong> You have exactly one day. Focus ruthlessly. Your Day One MVP is an 'Idle AWS GPU Instance Detector.'</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>CLI Tool:</strong> Build a simple Python (or Node.js) command-line interface.</li>
<li><strong>AWS Authentication:</strong> Require AWS credentials (e.g., <code>AWS_ACCESS_KEY_ID</code>, <code>AWS_SECRET_ACCESS_KEY</code> in environment variables) and a region.</li>
<li><strong>Instance Listing:</strong> Use <code>boto3</code> (or AWS SDK equivalent) to list all running EC2 instances in the specified region.</li>
<li><strong>GPU Instance Filtering:</strong> Filter this list to specifically identify instances known for AI/ML workloads, particularly those with GPUs (e.g., <code>p2</code>, <code>p3</code>, <code>g4dn</code> series instances).</li>
<li><strong>GPU Utilization Check:</strong> For each identified GPU instance, query AWS CloudWatch for the <code>GPUUtilization</code> metric over the last 24 hours.</li>
<li><strong>Idle Detection Logic:</strong> If the <em>maximum</em> <code>GPUUtilization</code> reported for a given instance over that 24-hour period is less than 5% (indicating near-idle status), flag it.</li>
<li><strong>Output:</strong> Print a clean, formatted list to the console showing: <code>Instance ID</code>, <code>Instance Type</code>, and a clear message: 'Potentially idle GPU instance – investigate for cost savings.' (Optional: an estimated hourly cost if you can hardcode common types or quickly fetch pricing).</li>
</ol>
<p>This MVP provides immediate, tangible value: identifying forgotten, expensive resources. It proves the core concept with minimal dependencies and no complex UI. The value is obvious: find idle GPU machines that are costing hundreds, if not thousands, of dollars per month. From here, you build out integrations, more complex detection, and beautiful dashboards.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>