<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:03:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: TextGraph: Unlock Knowledge from Plain Text with AI]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=qBihGjn_8L5ZzO3kCFpehLFiSeDMKfmtRvrE4p8Xc7C2ImY-e7IiGeCMvGWYgVfE</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=qBihGjn_8L5ZzO3kCFpehLFiSeDMKfmtRvrE4p8Xc7C2ImY-e7IiGeCMvGWYgVfE</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 May 2025 12:03:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Plain text files are the bedrock of many workflows – notes, documentation, code snippets, logs. Yet, they remain siloed, unstructured, and difficult to navigate beyond simple search. What if you could automatically turn this vast, flat landscape into a rich, interconnected knowledge graph, revealing hidden insights and relationships?</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong><br />
TextGraph is a concept for a tool that processes directories of plain text files (Markdown, TXT, code files, etc.) to automatically build a personal knowledge graph. Using AI techniques like named entity recognition (NER) and potentially future relationship extraction, it identifies key concepts, people, places, events, and other entities within your files and maps the connections between them and the files themselves.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong><br />
Transform scattered, unstructured plain text data into an intelligent, navigable graph structure. Discover implicit connections between your notes, projects, and ideas. Gain a contextual overview of your information landscape, moving beyond simple keyword search to explore relationships and themes automatically extracted by AI.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong><br />
Indie software developers, technical writers, researchers, students, lawyers, journalists, or any individual or small team that relies heavily on plain text files for managing knowledge and information.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a day):</strong><br />
The core idea is processing plain text with AI to get structured output. A viable MVP that demonstrates this <em>immediately</em> is:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Input:</strong> A command-line tool takes a single argument: a path to a local directory.</li>
<li><strong>Processing:</strong><ul>
<li>Recursively scan the provided directory for all files with <code>.txt</code> or <code>.md</code> extensions.</li>
<li>For each file found:<ul>
<li>Read its entire content.</li>
<li>Use a readily available open-source NLP library (like spaCy with its default English model) to process the text.</li>
<li>Extract all detected Named Entities (<code>doc.ents</code>) and their labels (e.g., PERSON, ORG, GPE).</li></ul></li></ul></li>
<li><strong>Output:</strong> Print to the console or save to a simple CSV/JSON file a list of tuples, each containing the file path, the extracted entity text, and the entity label.</li>
</ol>
<p><em>This MVP deliberately avoids building or visualizing the actual graph, which is complex. It focuses solely on the crucial first step: demonstrating automated extraction of structured entities from unstructured text using AI, providing the raw material for building the knowledge graph later. An indie developer familiar with Python and spaCy can implement this core text processing loop and output within a day.</em></p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>