<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:03:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: Plaintext Myth Weaver: AI for Narrative & Lore]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=Kqe_QKs_OoTYPc783P8s_1lNk9Rn36RuQXxTFaQXg7yxnCBfkO5CeBK3EydTXjG0</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=Kqe_QKs_OoTYPc783P8s_1lNk9Rn36RuQXxTFaQXg7yxnCBfkO5CeBK3EydTXjG0</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 18:03:15 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="the-idea-plaintext-myth-weaver">The Idea: Plaintext Myth Weaver</h3>
<p><strong>Brief description of the idea:</strong><br />
Imagine a stripped-down, focused application that takes your plain text prompts and, powered by advanced AI, expands them into rich, structured game lore, character backgrounds, or branching interactive narratives. It’s a dedicated assistant for game writers and designers who prefer working with plain text but crave the creative spark and expansion capabilities of AI.</p>
<p><strong>Core value proposition:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Rapid Prototyping:</strong> Instantly transform fragmented ideas into detailed, cohesive game lore or narrative structures, accelerating your world-building process.</li>
<li><strong>Unleash Creativity:</strong> Overcome writer's block with AI-generated suggestions, alternate plotlines, and expanded character arcs, always in a flexible, editable plain text format.</li>
<li><strong>Plain Text Power:</strong> Embrace the simplicity, portability, and future-proof nature of plain text (Markdown, YAML-like structures) as your core asset format, making integration with any game engine or toolset seamless.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Target customers:</strong></p>
<p>Independent game developers, aspiring game writers, tabletop RPG dungeon masters, and content creators focused on narrative-driven experiences. Anyone who dreams of rich worlds and compelling stories, but finds traditional game development tools too cumbersome for initial narrative design.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum viable product (MVP) scope which can be implemented in a day:</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Plain Text Input:</strong> A single, large text area (Markdown-enabled is a bonus) where the user types their initial prompt – a character concept, a historical event for their world, or the start of a story scene.</li>
<li>**</li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>