<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Food for Thought</title>
        <link>https://akngs.github.io/feed-bundler/food-for-thought</link>
        <description>Food for Thought</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:09:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <copyright>N/A</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Small Business Idea: API: Unstructured Text to Queryable Entities (Towards a Knowledge Graph)]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=E8VAFIAG1HgAw6RXQ4z3raQkN6dNKtlWJc6H1beZVeage8EleXGF_HV6aIIGWo8X</link>
            <guid>https://github.com/akngs/feed-bundler?guid=E8VAFIAG1HgAw6RXQ4z3raQkN6dNKtlWJc6H1beZVeage8EleXGF_HV6aIIGWo8X</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 00:09:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay, listen up.</p>
<p>The noise of unstructured information is drowning out valuable insights. Documents, notes, articles – they're full of connections we can't easily query or analyze. AI can help process this, and APIs can make it accessible. Combine them, and you start building queryable knowledge.</p>
<p>This year's idea:</p>
<p><strong>Brief Description:</strong></p>
<p>Build a simple API service that takes raw unstructured text (like notes, meeting minutes, articles) and processes it using basic AI (Natural Language Processing) to extract key entities (people, organizations, locations, etc.). The API's immediate value is providing a structured, machine-readable output of entities found in the text.</p>
<p><strong>Core Value Proposition:</strong></p>
<p>Turn messy, unsearchable text into structured data points. Enable developers and users to programmatically identify key actors, places, and concepts within any given text, laying the foundation for more advanced knowledge discovery, analysis, or graph construction.</p>
<p><strong>Target Customers:</strong></p>
<p>Indie developers, researchers, analysts, students, and small teams who need to extract structured data from text without building complex NLP pipelines themselves. Anyone dealing with information overload in text documents.</p>
<p><strong>Minimum Viable Product (MVP) Scope (Implementable in a Day):</strong></p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Technology Stack:</strong> Choose a simple backend framework (e.g., Flask, FastAPI, Express.js) and a cloud function service or local host setup.</li>
<li><strong>Core Function:</strong> Select <em>one</em> easily integrated, pre-trained NLP library (e.g., spaCy with a default model, or a cloud provider's basic NLP API if you have an account). Focus <em>only</em> on entity extraction (Named Entity Recognition - NER).</li>
<li><strong>API Endpoint:</strong> Create <em>one</em> POST endpoint (e.g., <code>/extract_entities</code>).</li>
<li><strong>Input:</strong> The endpoint accepts raw text in the request body.</li>
<li><strong>Processing:</strong> Pass the incoming text directly to the chosen NLP library's NER function.</li>
<li><strong>Output:</strong> Return a JSON response containing a list of the extracted entities, specifying their type (e.g., <code>[{ "text": "Apple", "type": "ORG" }, { "text": "Tim Cook", "type": "PERSON" }]</code>).</li>
<li><strong>No Persistence:</strong> Do <em>not</em> store the text or results in a database for this one-day MVP. Process the text and return the result immediately.</li>
</ol>
<p>That's it. An API that takes text and returns structured entities. It's basic, but it connects AI (NLP) with the API economy, and the list of entities is the simplest possible node list for a future knowledge graph. It proves the core concept: turning unstructured text into queryable data via an API.</p>]]></content:encoded>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>